

Suraj.Software Development Engineer

Being a software engineer I have close to 2 years of experience in the field of software development. Working with teams and on multiple domains is something I love the most and works continuously to keep myself updated with the changing technology.

🔾 Gaya, India

in linkedin.com/in/iamsuuraj

9113730080

iamsurajsingh.github.io/mypage

github.com/iamsurajsingh

WORK EXPERIENCE

Assistant System Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services

11/2019 - Present Achievements/Tasks Kolkata

- Platform: A web application that would work as an underwriter platform for the country's leading client in the field of Insurance.
- Worked on multiple domains, such as accounting, underwriting and finance.
- Single handedly delivered ~ 30+ features in a single year.

Front End Developer Intern Enigma Digital

06/2018 - 08/2018 New Delhi

Achievements/Tasks

 Worked as a Web Developer Intern to develop web pages by using scripting languages, overlooking some designs.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Portfolio v1.0

- Created a personalized portfolio website for myself to showcase a digital portfolio rather than old styled resume's.
- o Tech-Stack: HTML, CSS, React, Styled Icons
- URL: https://iamsurajsingh.github.io/mypage

Vaccine Availability Finder

- It was a tough task to find a vaccine slot by just sitting with the devices to book the slots from the CoWin website in the initial days. Developed a vaccine availability alert mechanism that triggered a mail to our email addresses with all the locations where slots where available.
- o Tech-Stack: Python, API, SMTP
- o Github: https://github.com/iamsurajsingh/VaccineAvailability

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology

Noida Institute of Engineering and Technology

08/2015 - 06/2019 Greater Noida

Courses

Information Technology

SKILLS



POSITION OF RESPONSIBILITES

Financial Solutions Developer (11/2019 - Present)

Created the complete premium design for the product and integrating it to calculate premium based on data from customer. Worked on the development of multiple covers, hierarchy and the business logic as per the regulation from IRDAI.

Production Support Developer (06/2021 - Present)

Handle all the development related defects in realtime that won't allow hampering of business to client. Solve all the low level to critical defects and deliver them post regression testing from testers. Each functionalities developed was made sure that it worked properly in sync with core and the portal.

CERTIFICATES

JavaScript Essentials (03/2021 - Present)

ORGANIZATIONS

Tata Consultancy Services (11/2019 - Present)

Enigma Digital (06/2018 - 08/2018)

Freelancing Tech Reviews & Blogs

LANGUAGES

nglish Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency Native or Bilingual Proficiency

INTERESTS

Travelling Knowing Places Tech Reviews